In the name of God, the Gracious, the Merciful. More and more people are
increasingly disillusioned with the Bible.
They grow up learning that the Bible is the Word of God.
But when they study the Bible carefully, they discover that it contains too many
unacceptable contradictions, too much unacceptable nonsense.
And this shocks them and causes the disillusionment.
A very good example is in the market today, in the bookstores.
We find a book by Carl Sagan called Contact, and on page 30 of this book, we find a very
good example of the contradictions, the unacceptable contradictions in the Bible.
We see here that in the Gospel of Matthew, there are 28
generations between David and Jesus. But in the Gospel of Luke, we see that the
number of generations from David to Jesus is 43. Now, how could this be the
word of God? Does God know how many generations are between David and Jesus?
The names in Matthew and in Luke are not even similar.
And this destroys the credibility of the Bible as the Word of God.
How can we explain these contradictions? This program will prove to you that the Bible
is in fact the Word of God. But these indefensible contradictions
are there because they were injected by human beings. Any contradiction, any
nonsense you see in the Bible, is a result of human interference, distortions
and injections by wicked people, or good intentioned people. So, I will prove to
you that the vast majority of the Bible is Divine truth.
The biggest contradiction of all is the deification of Jesus Christ,
making him a god against his will, and against the teachings of the Bible even.
We read in Matthew 27:46
that on the cross, toward mid-afternoon, Jesus cried out in a loud tone and the
Gospel of Matthew even write the Aramaic that Jesus supposedly uttered on the cross
ELI ELI LAMA SABACHTHANI? Which means
my God, my God, why have you forsaken me? Now, this is not God speaking, saying my
God, my God, why have you forsaken me? This also casts doubt and creates a serious
contradiction concerning the doctrine that Jesus came here to die for our sins.
Because if this were true, then his crucifixion would be a fulfillment of
his purpose and he would have said on the cross my God, my God, thank you for
fulfilling my mission. So, all these contradictions
create disillusionment in the minds of intelligent people. In this Bible here, we
find the theme at the beginning like this the man who hears my word and has
faith in Him who sent me, possesses eternal life. So, this verse is telling us
that Jesus was sent to humanity by God, that Jesus is a messenger of God.
And when we go to the book of Revelation, the very first verse says the following
This is the revelation God gave to Jesus Christ, that he might show his servants
what must happen very soon. This is the revelation God gave to Jesus Christ.
So, here we have God giving a message to Jesus Christ in order to deliver to the
world. Jesus could not possibly be God. Jesus is a messenger of God.
Many great Christians of course realized this serious contradiction, the deification of
Jesus against his will and studied it carefully and researched the
subject thoroughly. This book is written by Don Cupitt, a University Lecturer in
Divinity and Dean of Emmanuel College, Cambridge.
Michael Goulder, Staff Tutor in Theology in the Department of Extramural Studies at
Birmingham University. John Hick, who is H. G. Wood Professor of Theology
at Birmingham University. Leslie Houlden, Principal of Ripon College, Cuddesdon
Dennis Nineham, Warden of Keble College at Oxford.
Maurice Wiles, Regius Professor of Divinity and Canon of Christ Church
at Oxford, and Chairman of the Church of England's Doctrine Commission.
And the final author here is Frances Young, Lecturer in New Testament Studies
at Birmingham University. And the essence or the summary of the book is found on the
back where it says for many people, the incarnation of God in Jesus Christ
is the essence of Christianity. Here, a group of distinguished theologians
and biblical scholars asked whether the idea of the incarnation is essential to
Christianity and they questioned the whole development of the doctrine.
Their thesis is that Jesus was as he is described presented in Acts 2:21
a man approved by God for a special road within the divine purpose
and the later conception of him as God incarnate, the second person of the Holy
Trinity living a human life is a mythological or poetic way of expressing
his significance for us. This reinterpretation of the doctrine of the
incarnation has been criticized as sensational and destructive, but the
authors declare a constructive purpose. They have examined the evidence from the
New Testament onward with care and fairness and have asked their questions
because they are concerned with the consequences of their findings for a
full and living Christian faith for today. Their work is something that no
thinking Christian can ignore.
I assure you that we do not have enough time to give examples of the
contradictions and nonsense that is found throughout the Bible, unfortunately.
But you heard me state earlier that the Bible is in fact the Word of God, the
infallible Word of God. And here I am talking about the original unaltered
Bible in the original language. That was the Word of God.
The contradiction and the nonsense have been injected into the
Bible by people who deliberately or with good intentions actually distorted the
words of God and created doctrines that are not in the Bible. However, the Bible
as printed today, 90% of it is Divine truth. Unfortunately, the human race has
been duped into following the 10% of contradictions and false doctrines
injected by humans into the Bible. The Bible, being the Word of God, must be
corrected and God sees to it that all these contradiction and nonsense are exposed.
The biggest problem that these contradictions and nonsense create is
that millions of people throw the baby with the bathwater. Because of these
contradictions and false doctrines that have been injected in the Bible and the
nonsense that the intelligent people cannot accept, these things
unfortunately drive millions of people away from God and from the Word of God.
But we must be alerted that the Bible contains the truth from God. For example,
the first commandment in the Old Testament and in the New Testament which
is called the greatest commandment is to worship God alone, the Creator of the
universes, the Creator who created you and me and Jesus Christ and Muhammad and Mary.
It is the false doctrines that created
the Trinity and the deification of Jesus Christ against his will and distorted
the Bible. Ironically, the distortions and the nonsense and the false doctrines
constitute a minute part of the Bible. But unfortunately, millions upon millions of
people follow these minute contradictions and small false doctrines and they leave
the majority of the truth. They ignore, for example, the fact that the Bible
clearly states that Jesus is not God. Millions of people ignore the clear
statements throughout the Bible that Jesus is not God and they insist on the
deification of Jesus against his will. And in this way, they are being enemies of
Jesus Christ as he himself says in Matthew 7:23
Then I will tell them plainly, ‘I never knew you. Away from me, you evildoers!’ [Matthew 7:23]
Of course, God did something about the contradictions, the falsehood, the
nonsense that have been injected into His word, the Bible. And what God did was
to send a final edition of the scripture. This final edition is mathematically
composed beyond human ability, as I will explain to you. When you examine this
final message from God to you, you will be sure that every letter, every word is
from God. You will be absolutely positive that there is no human interference in
it and you will see which truth in the Bible is confirmed by this final segment
of the scripture and you will see that the contradiction and the false
doctrines are exposed. As such, you will recognize which is the
truth from God and which is the falsehood from human beings, human
interference into the Bible. So, this is what God did to clear the confusion, to
settle the controversies, and to establish the truth in His Bible.
This final segment of God's message to the world settles once and for all the
subject of the crucifixion of Jesus. And God tells us He was an eyewitness there, remember?
God tells us that the person of Jesus
Christ, that is the soul, left his body, was raised to God before his body was
put on the cross. So, the people who were torturing Jesus' body and crucifying it
were not dealing with Jesus Christ at all. Jesus was gone already. He was raised
like anyone who dies. The soul was raised, returned to God, and the body was
tortured and put on the cross. And the heart was beating and the lungs were
breathing, but the person was not there. Ironically, God gives us today a good
example of a person whose soul has departed but his body is living with us
and his heart is beating and his lungs are breathing, he's eating and he smiles
and everything, but his soul departed. And I am talking about one of the people who
received an artificial heart, Bill Schroeder. About a month after his
operation, he was having dinner with his wife and we are told he had a stroke.
In my opinion, Bill Schroeder left. The person is gone. And now his body is walking with
an artificial heart and his lungs are breathing but the person is not here. He
does not recognize the time or the people around him ever since that moment.
And this is exactly what happened regarding the crucifixion of Jesus, as
told in God's final message that is proven by mathematical code.
So, let me summarize for you what this final message from God to the world does.
First of all, it exposes the contradiction and the
nonsense that have been injected in the Bible.
The second thing, it confirms the Divine truths that are found in the Bible, the
majority of the Bible is Divine truth.
The third function of this final message from God to the world is to settle the
great controversies, like the deification of Jesus, the
sonship, the claimed sonship of Jesus to God.
The the fourth function of this final
segment of God's Scripture is to confirm all previous miracles, the unusual
happenings that cannot, that may be unbelievable, like the parting of the Red
Sea, like the fact that Jesus revived the dead, and created birds from clay by God's
leave. All these things are hard to believe. So, this final segment of God's Scripture
being mathematically composed and containing this physical evidence that
it is from God confirms those unusual happenings that we call miracles.
Since every letter, every word in this final segment of God's scripture is
mathematically composed beyond human ability, when you read a statement saying
Moses parted the Red Sea, this statement becomes proven by physical evidence. When
you read in this message that Jesus revived the dead, which is something
unbelievable, normally, when you read that and you know that it is a miracle...
miracle by definition is an unusual happening. So, when you read the statement
Jesus revived the dead, and you know that every letter, every word is
mathematically composed beyond the human ability, then this gives you
physical evidence that the statement Jesus revived the dead is a proven fact.
Unusual as it may be, it is God's miracle that Jesus performed. So, these are the
four functions of God's final scripture to the world. Expose the contradiction
and nonsense and remove it from the Bible.
Confirm the Divine truths that are contained in the Bible. Settle the
controversies like the virgin birth of Jesus and the crucifixion of his body
after his soul has departed. And the fourth function is to confirm
all previous miracles, the miracles of Moses and Jesus and the unusual
happenings that we see in the Bible and in the Quran.
I am sure you realize that we cannot cover these heavy subjects in such a
short time. And because these subjects are so heavy,
I am sure I raised more questions than answered. And this is why I hope you will
get on the phone and call me with your questions. Don't hesitate to ask. My phone (www.submission.ws)
number is area code 602 791 3989. I am going to put (www.submission.ws)
the address and the telephone number on the screen for you. So, please write or (www.submission.ws)
call. My address is 739 East 6th Street Tucson Arizona 85719. (www.submission.ws)
And the telephone is area code 602 791 3989 (www.submission.ws)
Thank you and God bless you. (www.submission.ws)